park-resorts.com 2019-06-17

# Privacy Policy | Data Protection | Parkdean Resorts

###  Purpose and introduction 

Parkdean Resorts is committed to respecting the privacy of its customers and processing your data responsibly. This Policy sets out how we, Parkdean Resorts UK Limited (as a data controller) and its associated group of companies1 (“we”, “us”, “our”) comply with our obligations under applicable data protection law.2 It aims to provide you information on how we collect and process your personal data, whether via our website, in connection with a booking or purchase with us or otherwise.

1Parkdean Resorts Limited, GB Holiday Parks Limited, Park Resorts Limited, Manor Park Holiday Park Limited, Southview Leisure Park Limited, South Lakeland Parks Limited, Lake District Leisure Pursuits Limited, Parkdean Holiday Parks Limited, Upperbay Limited, Parkdean Caravan Parks Limited, Southerness Holiday Village Limited, Weststar Holidays Limited and Vauxhall Holiday Park Limited.   
2General Data Protection Regulation (EU2016/679) as applicable and the Data Protection Act 2018

###  The personal data we collect about you 

Personal data is information about you and from which you can be identified. We will collect and process personal data about you in the course of our relationship with you as set out below.  Data Collection can be through a variety of channels, including by telephone, via our website, on site in our resorts and via third parties.

 **Type of data**|  **Description**  
---|---  
Identity Data| Name, username, age, gender, social media username (if you interact with us through those channels) and your car number plate (may be recorded at some of our parks for the purposes of safety and the prevention of crime)  
Contact Data| Address, email address and telephone numbers  
Financial Data| Bank account and payment card details  
Transaction Data| Details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us  
Technical | Information about your computer, tablet or mobile device including IP address, browser type, location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.

Usage of our website using a cookie file stored on the hard drive of your device being used to access the website. You are able to disable these cookies by changing your browser settings but this may slow down or prohibit access to certain parts or features of our website  
  
Profile| Purchases made by you, your interests, preferences, registration form details, information provided by you in connection with your stay, feedback, competition and survey responses  
Usage| Information on how you use our website, products and services including details of the bookings or purchases you make  
Marketing | Your preferences in receiving marketing communications from us  
CCTV | Footage in which you may feature when you visit one of our premises or parks  
Accident| If you have an accident whilst on our premises that you inform us of, we may record details of that accident and any injury you suffer in an accident log  
  
If you provide us with personal data about another person, you must ensure that before you do so, you have their agreement to do so and direct them to this Policy.

We may also collect information about you from third parties where this is relevant to our relationship with you. This includes obtaining personal data about you from third parties who provide us with the contact details of individuals who are interested in purchasing one of our caravans or lodges or booking a holiday or other related service with us.

We may require you to provide certain information to us in order to enter into and perform our contract(s) with you or to comply with our legal obligations. Except in these circumstances, your decision to provide personal data to us is generally voluntary and, where it is voluntary, you may choose to withhold and not provide personal data to us. If you choose not to provide certain information to us we may not be able to accomplish some of the purposes outlined in this Policy.

###  How will we use your information? 

We use your personal data in the course of our business and in connection with our relationship with you. In particular, your personal data may be used by us, our employees, contractors or agents, and disclosed to third parties. When we process your personal data, we must have a lawful basis for doing so. These are summarised below:

 **Legitimate interests**|  Means the interest of our business in conducting and managing it to enable us to give you the best possible service and experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests.   
---|---  
**Performance of a contract**|  This means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.  
 **Legal or regulatory obligation**|  Means processing your data where necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation to which we are subject.   
**Vital interests**|  Where necessary to protect someone’s vital interests (e.g. life or death)  
 **Consent**|  Where we have your valid consent  
  
For each of these purposes set out below, we have set out the legal basis on which we process your information.

 **Purpose**|  **Legal Basis (depending on the circumstances)**  
---|---  
To administer booking requests and purchases, including confirming your booking or purchase and otherwise communicating with you about your booking or purchaseThe recording of telephone calls for training and monitoring purposes to improve our service and train our people| 

  * performance of contract;
  * legitimate interests; or
  * consent 
  * legitimate interests

To provide you with other products and services you request| 

  * performance of contract;
  * legitimate interests; or
  * consent

To manage our relationship and to administer your membership to any membership scheme we provide| 

  * performance of contract;
  * legitimate interests; or
  * Consent

To help us to provide, review, develop and improve our products and services; this may include contacting you (including by email) for market research purposes| 

  * legitimate interests 

To provide you with information that you have requested from us| 

  * legitimate interests; or
  * consent

To send you marketing communications in order to boost and improve our business and encourage new and repeat bookings (as further described below)| 

  * legitimate interests; or
  * consent

To administer and contact you in relation to prize draws, competitions and other promotional activities| 

  * performance of contract;
  * legitimate interests; or
  * consent

To customise our website according to your interests and ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for your computer, tablet or mobile device| 

  * legitimate interests; or
  * consent

To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service where you have chosen to do so| 

  * legitimate interests; or
  * consent

To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences, including profiling, scoring and segmentation | 

  * legitimate interests; or

To address any claims made against us; for example, we may share details of our accident logs and CCTV footage with our insurers in connection with any claim made or likely to be made against us| 

  * legitimate interests; or
  * in connection with legal proceedings (i.e. the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims)

To comply with any legal or regulatory obligation (including in connection with a court order)| 

  * legal obligation

To enforce or apply the agreements we have with or otherwise concerning you (including agreements between you and us (or one or more of our group companies))| 

  * legitimate interests; 
  * legal obligation 

To protect our rights, property or safety or those of our customers, employees or other third parties (e.g. use the use of CCTV at some locations)| 

  * legitimate interests;
  * legal obligation; or
  * vital interests. 

###  When do we share your personal data? 

In connection with the uses referred to above, we may disclose your personal data to certain third parties, including:

  * Other companies and entities within the Parkdean Resorts’ group;
  * Services providers who provide IT services, wifi, system administration, feedback, marketing and market research services (e.g. to send postal mail, email and SMS, maintain and update our databases of customer details, analyse data, collate feedback, survey information, provide marketing assistance (including online targeted advertising), process card payments, provide customer service and handle claims);
  * Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services;
  * HMRC, regulators and other authorities who require reporting or processing activities in certain circumstances; 
  * Finance providers in the event that you purchase a holiday home;
  * To a seller or buyer in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets. In these circumstances, we may disclose personal data held by us to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets. If we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party (or subject to a reorganisation within our corporate group), personal data held by us will be one of the transferred assets; and
  * Other third parties to whom we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation (including in connection with a court order), or in order to enforce or apply the agreements we have with or otherwise concerning you (including agreements between you and us (or one or more of our group companies)); or to protect our rights, property or safety or those of our customers, employees or other third parties.

You should be aware that, if we are requested by the police or any regulatory or government authority investigating suspected illegal activities to access and disclose personal data concerning your activities whilst using our website, we reserve the right to do so. We also reserve the right to disclose personal data to third parties where a complaint arises concerning your use of our website, and that use is deemed by us inconsistent with the terms governing use of our website.

###  How long will we keep your personal data? 

We will only keep your personal data for as long as is necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the purpose for which it was collected and the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data and applicable legal requirements. 

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

###  Security 

We take the security of your personal data very seriously. We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent it from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. However, we would draw to your attention the fact that the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will endeavour to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website; any transmission is at your own risk.

We limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and where they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

###  Will we use your personal data for marketing purposes? 

Where you have enquired about booking a holiday or purchasing a holiday home or have booked a holiday or purchased a holiday home, we have a legitimate business objective in marketing to you to encourage new or repeat purchases. We will do so in compliance with both data protection and E-Privacy laws3. In accordance with your marketing preferences, we will use your personal data to send you newsletters and other marketing communications. We may also collect information about how you interact with our marketing communications (for example, whether you open emails we send to you). This helps us make our marketing more relevant to our customers. 

You have the right to object to the receipt of direct marketing at any time. You may do this by sending an email to us at [opt.out@parkdean-resorts.com](mailto:opt.out@parkdean-resorts.com) and enter 'Unsubscribe' in the subject line and indicating whether you wish to opt out of holiday marketing, holiday home sales marketing or both. 

Alternatively, you can unsubscribe from marketing email communications from us by following the unsubscribe instructions in each email that we send out. This will only unsubscribe you from marketing emails. If you wish to unsubscribe from other channels (post, telephone or SMS) please email [opt.out@parkdean-resorts.com](mailto:opt.out@parkdean-resorts.com). 

Please note that you may continue to receive marketing communications for a short period after changing your preferences while our systems are updated. 

If you opt out of receiving marketing information from us, we may still use your personal data to provide you with important service communications, including communications in relation to any bookings or purchases you make or in relationship to your ownership of a holiday home on a Parkdean Resorts Park.

In addition to the above, we may share limited personal data with advertising networks and other third parties to enable those networks and third parties to provide tailored advertising relating to Parkdean Resorts to you when you browse the internet and use third party services (such as social media platforms) on the basis of legitimate interests. 

3Including the Privacy and Electronic (EC Directive) Regulations 2003

###  Where will your personal data be processed? 

In relation to the above uses of your personal data and the above sharing arrangements, your personal data may be transferred to, and stored and processed in, one or more countries outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ). When we transfer your personal data outside of the EEA, we will ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by at least one of the following safeguards:

  * Where the European Commission has deemed that the country has an adequate level of protection for personal data;
  * The use of data transfer agreements (standard contractual clauses) approved by the European Commission;
  * Certification to the Privacy Shield framework (where the provider is based in the US); or
  * Another mechanism permitted by data protection law.

###  Third party websites 

This Policy relates only to information that we obtain from you. Our website contains certain links to other websites which may be of interest to you.

If you visit a website operated by a third party through a link included on this website, your information might be used differently by the operator of the linked website. You should look at that website’s privacy policy and take care, particularly if it requires you to submit personal data. 

Please also note that we are not responsible for the content that is displayed on these third party websites.

###  Use of Cookies 

Our website uses cookies. For more information, please see our Cookies Policy.

###  Your legal rights with respect to your personal data 

You have certain legal rights with respect to your personal data. These include the right to:

 **Request access**|  to your personal data (commonly known as a ‘subject access request’). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you.  
---|---  
 **Request correction**|  of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.  
 **Request erasure**|  of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. Note, however, that on occasion we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you at the time of your request.  
 **Object to processing**|  of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In certain cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.  
 **Request restriction of processing**|  This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: 

(a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy;   
(b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it;   
(c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or   
(d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.  
  
 **Request the transfer**|  of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.  
 **Withdraw consent**|  **at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case.  
  
Where you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact the Data Protection Officer (contact details below). You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee or refuse to comply with your request if it is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. 

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response. 

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally, it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

###  Questions 

The Data Protection Officer has responsibility for overseeing compliance with this policy. If you have any questions about this policy, how we handle your personal data or wish to exercise any of your rights listed above, please contact the Data Protection Officer (contact details below). You have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK's supervisory authority for data protection issues ([www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, appreciate the chance to listen to your concerns before you approach the ICO, so please contact us in the first instance. 

###  Contact 

Data Protection Officer  
Parkdean Resorts  
One Gosforth Park Way  
Gosforth Business Park  
Newcastle upon Tyne  
NE12 8ET

Telephone: 0191 256 0795  
Email: [DPO@Parkdean-Resorts.com](mailto:DPO@Parkdean-Resorts.com)

###  Changes to this Policy 

If we decide to change this Policy, we will post the updated policy on this website. The updated policy will take effect as soon as it is posted on our website. This Policy was last updated in October 2018.
